FERNANDO COSTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER











PROFILE

As an early career professional, I am hungry to learn, develop my skills and grow. I pride myself in my ability to communicate and work well with others. Through experience, I have proven my capability to deliver and be a successful leader.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python, JavaScript, Java

Frameworks

Django, Vue, React Native, Spring Boot, Alexa Skills Kit

Tools

Git, JIRA, Adobe Campaign, Knowi

Databases

PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server

Cloud

AWS

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership
Communication skills
Design Thinking
Creative Problem Solving
Teamwork
Time management
Fast learner
Self-motivated

LANGUAGES

English Portuguese

EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sun Life Financial | Oct 2021 - Present

- Working on a variety of initiatives associated with facilitating and improving marketing efforts, including enhancements to the Retail Client Engagement platform, used by 1300+ Sun Life Advisors
- Demonstrated ability to learn quickly, by self-learning Adobe Campaign before formal training took place, resulting in early contribution and praise from management

ASSOCIATE INNOVATION DEVELOPER

Sun Life Financial | Jan 2021 - Oct 2021

- Led initiative on several different prototypes, from ideation, through research, design and build, to improve the experience of clients on web and voice channels
- Developed "reminders on voice" to increase client engagement on the voice channel, converting it into a production feature for 500+ clients
- Responsible for the training and development of seven co-op students and three full-time employees, helping construct a high-performing team

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ANALYST

Nevvon | Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Led the research and analysis of various business intelligence tools, resulting in a successful purchase to introduce data & analytics within the company
- Streamlined customer support and marketing efforts, by creating meaningful reports and visualizations, surfacing relevant data to aid in decision making
- Worked closely with CTO and COO to discuss direction, priorities and progress

PERSONAL PROJECT

CO-FOUNDER & SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ☐

NowFantasy | Jan 2020 - Present

- Co-founded NowFantasy a company focused on improving digital fan engagement and experiences for sport leagues and teams through fantasy games, mobile and wep applications
- Current client includes the Canadian Elite Basketball League, for which NowFantasy was the official fantasy provider of the 2021 CEBL Playoffs, as well as the developer of their upcoming mobile app CEBL Mobile

EDUCATION

HONOURS BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sheridan College | 2016 - 2021 | Honours Standing - 3.81 GPA

BOARD UNDERGRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN CREATIVITY AND CREATIVE PROBLEM SOLVING A Sheridan College | 2016 - 2021

SHAD CANADA ALUMNI

University of British Columbia SHAD | 2013